Mss.Rec.2 Mss.Rec.2
American Philosophical Society
- Audio recordings
  - A short story about a war concerning the French and the Tuscaroras, 1948-08-31; 08-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:47; Printup, Denny; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Includes some singing and some English.
    Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora Indians--Music; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); United States--History--French and Indian War, 1755-1763
  - A short story about a war concerning the French and the Tuscaroras, 1948-08-31; 08-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:28; Printup, Denny; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Includes some Tuscarora singing.
    Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora Indians--Music; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); United States--History--French and Indian War, 1755-1763
  - The Devil's Story, 1948-08-31; 08-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:08; Printup, Denny; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Devil--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The Devil's Story, 1948-08-30; 08-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:53; Printup, Denny; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    "General outline of story: man bet devil his heart/soul he cd build a house by dawn (cock-crow). He was able to do so, and save his soul, but the devil in anger tore down the house." Wire became tangled during recording, causing part of the story to be lost.
    Devil--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - History of the Laila Jimerson murder trial, 1949-07-11; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:25; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Indian Defense League of America; Murder; Trials (Murder)--New York (State); Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - History of the Laila Jimerson murder trial, 1949-07-11; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:25; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Indian Defense League of America; Murder; Trials (Murder)--New York (State); Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The being called Odakche, 1949-07-11; 09-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:12; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Monsters--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The being called Odakche, 1949-07-11; 09-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:07; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Monsters--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Old-time arrangements for marriage, 1949-07-11; 09-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:51; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Marriage; Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Old-time arrangements for marriage, 1949-07-11; 09-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:09; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Marriage; Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - How in the old days witches would tip over canoes going down the rapids in the St. Lawrence, 1949-07-11; 09-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:34; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Canoes and canoeing; Saint Lawrence River; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); Witches--Folklore
  - How in the old days witches would tip over canoes going down the rapids in the St. Lawrence, 1949-07-11; 09-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:49; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Canoes and canoeing; Saint Lawrence River; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); Witches--Folklore
  - A dwarf which helped the people, 1949-07-11; 09-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:29; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Spoken in English and then given in Tuscarora. Tuscarora begins at 00:56
    Dwarfs--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - A story about a dwarf deer and Devil's Hole, 1949-07-11; 09-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:39; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Given in Tuscarora and then in English. English begins at 01:28.
  - Thematic Apperception Test given by William MtPleasant, 1949-07-18; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:01; Mt. Pleasant, William; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Psychological tests; Thematic Apperception Test; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Continuation of Thematic Apperception Test by William MtPleasant, 1949-07-14; 10-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:37:06; Mt. Pleasant, William; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - Life history of Clinton Rickard [1 of 2], 1949-07-21; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:40:40; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    On childhood, education, brother, enlistment, on service in Phillipines during the Philippine-American war In both English and Tuscarora. Includes some interview questions in English.
    Military service, Voluntary--United States; Spanish-American War, 1898; Tuscarora Indians--Education; Tuscarora Indians--Social life and customs; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Life history of Clinton Rickard [2 of 2], 1949-08-22; 11-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:51; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Philippines--Description and travel; Philippines--History--Philippine American War, 1899-1902; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Life history of Clinton Rickard: Capturing a Filipino camp at night, 1949-08-22; 11-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:46; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Autobiography; Philippines--History--Philippine American War, 1899-1902; Tuscarora Indians--Biography; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Life history of Clinton Rickard: Life during the Army of Occuption in the Philippines, 1949-08-22; 11-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:33; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Autobiography; Philippines--Description and travel; Philippines--History--Philippine American War, 1899-1902; Tuscarora Indians--Biography; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Life history of Clinton Rickard: How the Filipinos lived, 1949-08-22; 11-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:16; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - Thematic Apperception Test of Mrs. Nellie Gansworth, 1949-07-22; 12-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:53:43; Gansworth, Nellie; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - Life history of Clinton Rickard: How the Filipinos planned a surprise attack, 1949-07-22; 13-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:13; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Autobiography; Military service, Voluntary--United States; Philippines--History--Philippine American War, 1899-1902; Tuscarora Indians--Biography; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Life history of Clinton Rickard: The surrender of some Filipino troops, 1949-07-22; 13-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:32; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - Life history of Clinton Rickard: Leaving the Philippines, 1949-07-22; 13-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:41; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Autobiography; Military service, Voluntary--United States; Philippines--Description and travel; Philippines--History--Philippine American War, 1899-1902; Tuscarora Indians--Biography; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Life History of Clinton Rickard: Getting an audience with Governor Roosevelt for the Cayugas, 1949-07-22; 13-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:37; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Autobiography; Cayuga Indians; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Tuscarora Indians--Biography; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - A story about a ghost, 1949-07-24; 13-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:10; Rickard, Edgar; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Ghost stories; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The political and economic situation of the reservation when the informant came back after being in the army, 1949-08-17; 13-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:49; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Tuscarora Indians--Economic conditions; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora Indians--Politics and government; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The political and economic situation of the reservation when the informant came back after being in the army, 1949-08-17; 13-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:59; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Tuscarora Indians--Economic conditions; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora Indians--Politics and government; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The dispute over the Canadian Indians, 1949-08-17; 13-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:16; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Concerns Iroquois Indians living in Canada and a disupte regarding their rights under the Jay Treaty of 1794 to cross the border freely.
    Great Britain. Treaties, etc. United States, 1794 Nov. 19; Indians of North America--Canada; Indians of North America--Civil rights--History; Indians of North America--Legal status, laws, etc.; Tuscarora Indians--Politics and government; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The dispute over the Canadian Indians, 1949-08-17; 13-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:50; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Great Britain. Treaties, etc. United States, 1794 Nov. 19; Indians of North America--Canada; Indians of North America--Civil rights--History; Tuscarora Indians--Politics and government; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Leaving the Council, leading up to the formation of the Defense League, 1949-08-17; 13-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:29; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    In Tuscarora, followed by English re-telling. English begins at 03:21
    Indian Defense League of America; Tuscarora Indians--Politics and government; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Tuscarora story about a fox and a dog, 1949-07-24; 14-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:00; Rickard, Edgar; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Dogs--Folklore; Foxes--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Tuscarora story about a race between a fox and a crawfish, 1949-07-24; 14-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:30; Rickard, Edgar; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Crayfish--Folklore; Foxes--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Tuscarora story about a fox, a fish peddler, and a bear, 1949-07-24; 14-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:12; Rickard, Edgar; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Bears--Folklore; Foxes--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Tuscarora story about a Great Spirit, 1949-07-24; 14-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:40; Rickard, Edgar; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - Tuscarora story about the Niagara River, 1949-07-24; 14-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:51; Rickard, Edgar; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Fishing; Niagara River (N.Y. and Ont.); Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Tuscarora story about when General Peter A. Porter was captured by the British and rescued by the Indians, 1949-07-24; 14-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:55; Rickard, Edgar; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    The individual identified on the recording as General Peter A. Porter is actually Peter Buell Porter.
    Porter, Peter B. (Peter Buell), 1773-1844; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); United States--History--War of 1812
  - How they appoint chiefs in the Tuscarora Nation, 1949-07-24; 14-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:34; Rickard, Edgar; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Tuscarora Indians--Politics and government; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - A story about a woman accused of being a witch, and a story about obedience, 1949-07-24; 14-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:22; Rickard, Edgar; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Second story begins at 07:19
    Obedience--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); Witches--Folklore
  - A story about a ghost, 1949-07-24; 14-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:26; Rickard, Edgar; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - The old story of Fort Cayanuki, 1949-08-25; 15-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:45; Rickard, Edgar; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Begins with informal conversation in English and Tuscarora. Chief Rickard also referred to as Chief Twenty-Canoe, according to him. Refers to Peter Buell Porter, mistakenly referred to as Peter A. Porter. English version begins at 11:59
    Porter, Peter B. (Peter Buell), 1773-1844; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); United States--History--War of 1812
  - The killing of Frebur[?], 1949-08-25; 15-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:38; Rickard, Edgar; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); United States--History--French and Indian War, 1755-1763
  - A witch story and a story about a snake, 1949-08-25; 15-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:03; Rickard, Edgar; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Snakes--Folklore; Tuscarora Indians--Folklore; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); Witches--Folklore
  - About two dreams, 1949-08-25; 15-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:15; Rickard, Edgar; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Dreams; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The Indians devised a plan to extinguish the poisonous snakes, 1949-08-25; 15-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:52; Rickard, Edgar; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
  - Rorschach of Chief Edgar Rickard, 1949-08-25; 16-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:08:50; Rickard, Edgar; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    Also includes informal conversation in English. Stories on Indian Council, New York state politics and politicians.
    Autobiography; New York (State)--Politics and government--20th century; Tuscarora Indians--Biography; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora Indians--Politics and government; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)